Seek the truth.
The Da Vinci Code is a thriller, mystery film directed by Ron Howard.
A murder in Paris’ Louvre Museum and cryptic clues in some of Leonardo da Vinci’s
most famous paintings lead to the discovery of a religious mystery.
For 2,000 years a secret society closely guards information that — should it
come to light — could rock the very foundations of Christianity.
Robert Langdon, played by Tom Hanks.
Sophie Neveu, played by Audrey Tautou.
Sir Leigh Teabing, played by Ian McKellen.
Captain Bezu Fache, played by Jean Reno.
Silas, played by Paul Bettany.
Bishop Manuel Aringarosa, played by Alfred Molina.
The Da Vinci Code is a 2006 mystery thriller film directed by Ron Howard, written by
Akiva Goldsman, and based on Dan Brown's 2003 novel of the same name.
The first in the Robert Langdon film series, the film stars Tom Hanks, Audrey Tautou, Ian
McKellen, Alfred Molina, Jürgen Prochnow, Jean Reno, and Paul Bettany.
In the film, Robert Langdon, a professor of religious symbology from Harvard University, is the
prime suspect in the grisly and unusual murder of Louvre curator Jacques Saunière.
On the body, the police find a disconcerting cipher and start an investigation.
Langdon escapes with the assistance of police cryptologist Sophie
Neveu, and they begin a quest for the legendary Holy Grail.
Sir Leigh Teabing, a noted British Grail historian, tells them that the actual Holy Grail
is explicitly encoded in Leonardo da Vinci's wall painting The Last Supper.
Also searching for the Grail is a secret cabal within Opus Dei, an actual prelature of the Holy See,
who wish to keep the true Grail a secret to prevent the destruction of Christianity.
The film, like the book, was considered controversial.
It was met with especially harsh criticism by the Catholic Church for the accusation that it is behind a two-thousand-year-old cover-up concerning what the Holy Grail really is
and the concept that Jesus Christ and Mary Magdalene were married, producing a daughter, as well as its treatment of the organizations Priory of Sion and Opus Dei.
Many members urged the laity to boycott the film.
In the book, Brown states that the Priory of Sion and "all descriptions of artwork,
architecture, documents and secret rituals in this novel are accurate".
The Da Vinci Code premiered as the opening film of the 59th Cannes Film Festival on May
17, 2006, and was theatrically released in the United States on May 19.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, but was a commercial success, grossing $224 million in its worldwide opening weekend and an initial total of $760
million worldwide against a $125 million production budget, becoming the second-highest-grossing film of 2006, as well as Howard's highest-grossing film to date.
It was followed by two sequels, both directed by Howard:
Angels & Demons (2009) and Inferno (2016).
The film explores themes of paris, france, based on novel
or book, holy grail, christianity, monk.
The tone is uplifting and mind_bending and thought_provoking.